## PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Agile Workflow
Project Management
Software Testing
Visual Studio Code
Web Development Projects
CMS Management
Responsive Design
Graphic Design Integration

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

Creative spirit
Reliable and professional
Organized
Time management
Team player
Fast learner
Motivated

#### VOLUNTEER EXPERIANCE

I Grow Chicago Jan 2019 - Present Health, Civil Rights and Social Action

#### CONTACT

P: 773-875-5954
E: dblue@icstars.org
L: www.linkedin.com/in/darrell-blue/
W: www.DarrelBlue.tk

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
John Hopkins University | January 2022

Web Programming Foundation LinkedIn Learning | Sep 2021

Scrum: The Basics LinkedIn Learning | Aug 2021

# DARRELL BLUE

### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Inventive Web Developer creates novel site designs and innovative user interfaces. Known for architecting customer-facing products that deliver unique experiences while complying with internal coding standards and technical requirements. Clever provider of fresh assets to grow user ship. while bringing superior front- and back-end design to promote organization-specific website presence. Thorough comprehension of complex HTML, CSS, and JavaScript programming languages to generate custom webpage design.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

SOLUTIONS WEB DEVLOPER

Nansen | Sept 2021 - Current

- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Ran debugging tools such as Firebug and Chrome Inspector to eliminate flaws and glitches prior to publishing.
- Conducted functional testing over course of the web development lifecycle.
- Drafted customized layout and wireframes based on predetermined parameters and expectations.

#### TECHNICAL INTERN

i.c.stars | March 2021 - Current

- Created and implemented RPA procedures to aid in the reduction of errors by 99%.
- Developed and maintained quality assurance procedure documentation.
- Collected and analyzed activity data and initiated, developed, and recommended improvements to systems, processes, and procedures to increase productivity and reduce cost.

#### OWNER OPERATOR

Blue Vision Booth | Jan 2016 - March 2020

- Managed 5 employees by supervising daily tasks.
- Devised, deployed, and monitored processes to boost long-term business success and increase profit levels by 50% over the first year.
- Owned day-to-day business operations including accounting, finance, human resources, and marketing.
- Stayed current with market trends to determine optimal pricing to capitalize on emerging opportunities.

#### EDUCATION

#### ARCHITECTURE

University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign | 2008 - 2012